hi everybody welcome back to Polar Ice
Creamery we're going to go down the
chocolate series again now we've got
lots of new cocoa powders to try we're
going to treat them all like we
did very early in the chocolate series
we're going to get some milk warmed up
get some cocoa powder mixed into all of
them and then try them
first
[Music]
okay so in order
the
Rodell which came from
Costco Hershey's dark the giradelli and
Seven Hills if you've watched my channel
before you will know what this one is
about but all all three of these are
medium fat cocoa powders so 10% is um
there is apparently some variation from
batch to batch for this one uh and this
one but this one is 16 to 177% Fat so a
little bit higher it's a it's an unusual
kind of place to put fat content for 16
17% normally it's 22 to 24 and 10 to 12
and then down to your ones or less
having something in between is is
unusual but you as you can see they're
very
different colors I'm going to snap a
little picky
here and
then you can
see that this one so the Seven Hills is
much lighter in color actually they kind
of go down in color gray don't they
that's light and then dark and
everything in between
um Hershey's dissolved much easier than
the others but let's try them so seven
heels
first it's got a great flavor 7 Hills
cocoa
powder organic cacao powder
apparently is it's a very milky taste
this is the COA powder to use if you
want to create an exact copy of hug
andar Belgian
chocolate this one if that's your
favorite ice cream store bought ice
cream order this from Amazon pay the
import and be done with it this is how
you create it giradelli
it's a great
taste it's definitely darker in flavor
so it's a heavier cocoa powder you can
tell it's got slightly higher fat
content but it's still got a Milky kind
of taste to it so somewhere in between
and that the fat content doesn't really
dictate whether you've got a milk
chocolate flavor or dark chocolate
flavor there's a lot of things that go
into that the the amount of alkalization
that's used in Dutch processed cocoa I
don't I don't know if this one is Dutch
process maybe not but this one is all
the other ones are
Hershey's it's actually in that form and
not too bad I just I'm just not a big
fan of it in ice
cream maybe it makes a good hot
cocoa and then Rodell which is brand new
never tried
it darker deeper
it's got a it's definitely got a more
complex flavor like the giradelli
they've got more complex flavors those
two so that's these two
here Hershey's has got very flat flavor
it's it's not got a very deep flavor
profile and neither does Seven Hills but
with such a Milky flavor it doesn't
surprise
me it's still an excellent
taste
so
those
three
are really good this
one just not a fan of it sorry if you
like Hershey's if you like
Hershey's use it you don't like any of
these just use whatever cooca pad you
like you know but if you chocolate ice
cream is about what you want it's about
the type of chocolate flavor that you're
looking for if you're making if you want
to make that henar Bon chocolate use
this there is no substitute use this one
okay that that will get you the exact
copy but now that we've tried these
we're going to make
a base chocolate ice cream
using this one
Rodell okay it's got a nice strong
flavor and what we're going to do is
we're going to copy I've got it in front
of the on the screen in front of me here
we're going to copy the
valona chocolate earlier in the
chocolate series we're going to modify
that recipe because this is slightly
different fat
content
and we'll see what it's like
so let's do
it that's better what do we need for
this chocolate ice cream
so we need a pan we're going
to move these out the
way we're going to copy with adjustments
come
on thank you so we need 450 G of milk
and we need our
cream how much cream do we
need we need 550 so this is modified
compared to the last one because I made
the last one
with double cream in
England I love English double
cream
550 English double cream is 50% fat
content okay and that's not an
exaggeration it it is 50% fat content
450 G this is
of
milk should have got a bigger
pan there we go
4503 close
enough G of milk there's our liquid
elements now we need the dry
ingredients so let's just get all of
these out what do we need we need 100 g
of sugar haven't got the
sugar
100 100 g of
sugar we need 80 g
of dexos oh I shouldn't have done the
bag up so tight let's see if I can there
we
go 80 gram of dextrose
we need 60 G of skim milk
powder
and 65 G of cocoa
there we go
stay 65
[Music]
G
now ordinarily I'd put these into the
pot as it's going but because we're
running low on
room which
you see me do a lot we're going to put
all of this and all of this into one pot
okay and this is a nice way to get
around did we use stabilizer yes we did
use our stabilizer so here we go
again where have I put it oh it's over
there
stabilizer stabilizer in chocolate ice
cream it's actually really important
chocolate ice cream is one of the
hardest ice creams to make
well because
it a freezes very
hard 2 G of stabilizer same amount I
used in the first video um chocolate ice
cream freezes very hard because the
additional fat in the
mixture um little whisk I think the
additional
fat and most people don't account for
that in their
recipes so you kind of need to be a
little bit
careful it's all of it in there we're
going to stir it all
up together so we've got a cocoa sugar
milk powder dexos
stabilizer
mix doesn't need to be perfect
perfect but all of that has somehow got
to go in this tiny little Gap I've got
the top of the pan all right so what
we're going to do now is we're going to
get
this on the hob and get it all heated
up okay we're just going to add our
mixture into
our add our dry ingredients into our wet
ingredients that's what they say on the
professional channels isn't it
only
just and we're going to gently get that
stirred in
and we don't really need to apart from
stabilizers we don't need to do anything
other than dissolve the cocoa you do
like to or you should Bloom cocoa in
Dairy for a little bit but as we need to
bring this up to you know 70 80° for the
stabilizer it's going to happen anyway
so I'm going to keep stirring this to
make sure it doesn't go over the edge
and then
then we'll get it in a in a container in
the fridge Okie do so we've heated our
base up to
80° that allowed the cocoa to
bloom all the ingredients to dissolve
for me to make a mess I don't know how
I'm going to get this in here wish me
luck one two 3 slowly does
it and there we
go we did
it
and just going to let this cool down in
the fridge it'll likely be what time is
it now see it's 10 5 I'm not going to
make this
today uh I'll come back to this tomorrow
and we'll Churn it up I might even knock
up some brownies to so that we can do a
combo we can do a straight out at the
tub chocolate ice cream comparison
and then with some brownie pieces in
there for a chocolate fudge brownie so I
will see you
tomorrow we're on to the chocolate
churning part now if you're a t-shirt
Watcher then you'll notice that I'm
actually doing this at the same time as
the last week's video which was the har
andar strawber cheesecake so it's an
entire day of making ice cream today uh
this been in the fridge overnight this
is the
Rodell cocoa
powder
you got be 7t tall to reach up there
this this is it this is the the one
we're using
here um oh look it matches the matches
the
bowl much like I said
previously this recipe is been done to
mirror the valona chocolate recipe that
we did the other year last year I think
it was um that Alona
chocolate was the best chocolate ice
cream is it the best chocolate ice cream
I don't know it's right up there it's
right up there with the best chocolate
ice cream I've
eaten so we got to give this a shot
you'll notice there's High dextrose in
this because chocolate goes quite hard
when you freeze it or chocolate ice
cream goes quite hard when you freeze it
so by reducing the amount of su Ros
increasing the amount of dextrose you
can play with the freezing point and
make it a little bit easier to scoop
don't all dextr it would just be liquid
so we're going to give this one little
mix up nice viscosity straight out the
fridge nice strong smell too it's got a
good
color it's a solid medium
brown nice happy with
that yep so we're good to go pre-chilled
for 10 minutes let's get this in here
get it
churning and see where we end
[Music]
up
time to Dish up some chocolate ice cream
this is the
Rodell Costco cocoa
powder put that right there
um all cocoa powers are different
they are they they it's irrelevant to a
degree what the fat content
is you've got some with you know 0.1%
fat some with 1% fat then you've got
some the late single digits the majority
fall into the 10 to 12% fat range and 20
to 24% fat range somewhere there but
then you've also got like the girad deli
which is 16 17% so it's all over the
place and there's no
reason
why they all shouldn't taste
good they're all processed different
some the majority that I use are Dutch
process which is treated with an
alkaline
solution um you don't have to use Dutch
process Coke if you don't want to use
whatever Coco you like guitard is
excellent valona is obviously very very
good you've got urco which is great
cabar brute which is great giradelli
great you know all of these that make
really really good ice creams and even
some of the cheapest ones you know that
one that I had imported over here from
the
UK the Seven Hills it it's an excellent
POS yeah possibly the best so far I
found to make a milk chocolate ice cream
with it's the perfect flavor it's not
expensive all coca palor is expensive in
Canada regardless of what type it is and
where you buy it from I don't know why
it's expensive over here but it is in
the UK you could buy a kilo bag of
really top quality cocoa for less than
10 um £10 is
what6 Canadian dollars at the moment if
you wanted to buy a a kilo of the same
cocoa powder in Canada and it doesn't
matter whereabouts in Canada you are
it's a little bit cheaper if you're in
nario but um for the majority you're
looking at
253 bucks which is crazy
none of these are from England by the
way they all come from other parts of
Europe so I don't know why the the cost
is so high but America having giradelli
excellent excellent cocoa powder that
should be your go-to if you're
struggling for a decent quality cocoa
powder not
Hershey's anyway I've yed on enough
let's
scoop
[Music]
it looks excellent using the cocoa you
get that real whacka chocolate flavor
and it doesn't freeze quite so hard it's
melting in the bowl nicely it's
surprisingly warm here considering it's
October let's see what this one tastes
like oh smooth
it's a really smooth chocolate ice cream
it's got a
lovely it's got a really nice
taste it doesn't have the fudgin
that that valona and gards give you and
valona gives you a fudgier chocolate ice
cream than guitars does but it does have
a nice flavor considering this is a
budget brand Coco can't moan about that
at all I don't even know how much it
cost I bought so much crap at Costco it
was you
know I'll put the price up on the screen
here but you've got a well-rounded
chocolate
flavor I probably would say maybe
increase the stabilizer just a touch or
maybe just a little bit more milk
powder you know I'm super hard on the
ice cream
results anyway uh my wife points this
out to me all the time that sometimes
other people have no idea what I'm
moaning about and it's perfect to them
but to me I can pick out all the miny
little floors it's the tiniest tiniest
little
touch I'm not even going to call it ice
cuz it's
not yeah I I just what I'm going to do
is I'm going to adjust the description
below to what I think would make this
perfect it's so close like 98% there but
a really really nice chocolate ice cream
very well-rounded flavor great mouth
feel lasting flavor too still lingering
now cheap as well to buy
so nice nice one to try it's probably
you
know right in the middle of cocoa powder
so far it's not amazing but it's
certainly not bad
if you want to try it give it a BH
thanks very much for joining don't
forget to like And subscribe I'll see
you next
[Music]
week